原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译     千只鹤飞过波千鸟  tong大梨  AlgerDestiny
翻译     五天  A序列  不见东东  VioletCheng
校对     屯栗子
时间轴     西·查
后期     渔夫
总监     屯栗子
辛普森一家
第三十一季  第十三集
老谋子酒馆
阿壳汉堡
我以前没见过你
I haven't seen you before.
我们走啊走  跳跳跳
Yeah, we go around-- jumping, jump, jump.
我们快活  哈哈
Oh, we bouncy ba-- ha, ha.
放狗
Release the hounds.
兰特尔餐馆
我好开心春田镇终于有了一家素食餐馆
I'm so excited Springfield finally has a vegan restaurant.
我就知道你会很开心的  丽莎
I thought you'd enjoy this, Lisa.
你完全有权利选择只有自己喜欢的食物
You deserve to have the food that only you like.
您的圣路易小勒排
Your St. Louis-style Baby Back Fibs,
山药腿以及和牛糯
leg of yam and Wagyu beets.
老爸  你确定你想在这里吃饭吗
Dad, are you sure you're okay eating here?
我什么都能吃
I can eat anything
只要我想象它有脸
as long as I pretend it once had a face.
和眼睛
And eyes.
你们俩为什么都拍丽莎马屁
Why are you both kissing up to Lisa?
这是她的最后一餐吗
Is this her last meal?
你会希望自己在棺材里身材苗条
You're gonna want to look thin in your coffin,
所以我替你解决甜点
so I'll eat your dessert.
行啊  吃了我的甜点  你就跟老爸一样
Sure, have my dessert. You'll look like Dad.
回答你的问题  我们没有拍她马屁
And for your information, we are not kissing up.
顺便问一句  丽莎  你的作文
By the way, Lisa, have you picked a subject yet
"我认识最有趣的人"选好主题了吗
for your "Most Interesting Person I Know" paper?
谜团已解决
Aha! Mystery solved.
又一次  学校挑拨家长们反目成仇
Once again, the school pits parents against each other.
侯默  该你上了  自卖自夸吧兄弟
Homer, you're up. Sell yourself, dude.
丽莎你好  我是侯默·辛普森  你的大粉丝
Lisa, hi. Homer Simpson, longtime fan.
做过宇航员  偶尔纳税人
Astronaut, sometime taxpayer.
好吧  大家听听看
Oh, well, let's see,
"我认识最有趣的人是个白人男性"
"The most interesting person I know is a white male."
现今的语境下这么写挺合适呢
That'll go over great in today's climate.
但愿你喜欢遭反噬
I hope you like blowback.
老爸老妈  我已经决定好了
Mom, Dad, I've made my decision.
经过一番苦苦搜寻之后  我决定写
After a lot of soul-searching, I've decided to go with...
付临客  我要写付教授
Frink! I'm writing about Professor Frink.
谁
Who?
就是那个...
You know. "Flavin, glayvin, hoyvik."
那个有牙齿的可乐瓶人
That Coke bottle with teeth?
他的一生都致力于用科学使世界更美好
He's devoted his life to helping the world through science.
话说  我能退居第二或者第三不
Say, uh, can you tell me if I came in second or third?
咱们还是别问的好
It's best not to proceed down that road.
好  那我可以终结这场素食假戏了
Fine. Then I can end this little vegan charade.
春田大学
外来思想禁止入内
门萨健康[高智商组织]
付教授  我非常感谢
Professor Frink, I want to thank you so much
你让我在工作时间拜访你
for letting me visit you during office hours.
上个拜访他的
His last visitor was the process server
是替告他的猴子送诉讼传票的人
for the monkey who's suing him.
这是谁
who's this?
那是海丝勒教授
Oh, well, that's Professor Hessler.
我们共用办公室
We share the space here.
不用在意她  她研究人文学科
Pay her no mind. She's in the humanities.
付教授  我很想知道
Professor Frink, I'd love to know
你是如何开始涉足科学的
how you got started in science.
科学  我就是由科学创造的  孩子
Oh, science? Well, I was created by science, my dear child.
付教授
第一个试管婴儿降生
那是你吗
That was you?
不不  我是全世界第二个试管婴儿
Oh, no, no, I was the world's second test-tube baby.
所以没那么多人注意到我了
Yes, I-I was greeted with far less fanfare.
第二个是个呆子
我父母都很会"搞化学反应"
My parents had great chemistry.
不是爱的化学反应  他们是化学家
Uh, no love, but they were chemists.
我唯一可以博得关注的方法是通过科学
The only way I could get noticed was through science
和改变声音音量
and changing the pitch of my voice
这样他们就不可能注意不到我了
so they couldn't help but notice me.
但是我一直没有突破
But I never had my breakthrough.
在这个满是爱因斯坦的世界里
In a world of Einsteins,
我是詹姆斯·查德威克
I am a James Chadwick.
-谁  -你看  就是这样
- Who? - Well, exactly.
你没有出名实在是太糟糕了
It's too bad your name isn't famous.
这一切都会改变的
All this will change,
因为我一直在开发属于自己的加密货币
for I have been developing my own cryptocurrency.
我不知道这是什么意思
I have no idea what that means.
他们在学校都教你们什么
What do they teach you at that school?
如何给老师倒咖啡
How to get the teachers coffee.
总之  我要链接到电视里最受欢迎的科学家
Yeah-- A-Anyway, I will explain cryptocurrency by clicking
来解释加密货币  有请吉姆·帕森斯先生
a link to TV's most beloved scientist, Mr. Jim Parsons.
人们觉得我是个呆子
People think I'm a nerd,
但是我实际上超级酷
but I'm actually super cool.
所以我来讨论一下真正酷的学科
That's why I'm here to talk about the really cool subject
基于一致性算法的分布式加密货币
of distributed consensus-based cryptocurrency.
想不到吧
Kachinga.
书呆子能做到吗  我可不这么认为
Could a nerd do that? I don't think so.
为了让加密货币发挥作用
For cryptocurrency to work,
我们需要记录下所有的交易记录
we need a record of every transaction that occurs.
这些被记录在分布式账本里
These are recorded in what's called a distributed ledger.
*我是分享和同步共识的产物*
*电子数据*
不是呆子
*多平台分发*
*从上海*
*到格林纳达*
*每天我都更进一步*
*即将成为未来货币*
*并不存在于你的钱包里*
*我在你的计算机里*
当你使用货币的时候
When you use the currency,
交易记录在账本里
the transaction is recorded in the ledger.
我能挖掘出来
I can dig it.
一个账本记满之后
And when one ledger book gets filled up,
《生活大爆炸》残留物
我们把之前的账本链起来
we add to a "chain" of previous books.
这就是"区块链"
That's the "blockchain."
拜拜了  小故障们
Later, glitches.
如果你想了解更多关于加密货币的知识
If you'd like to learn more about how cryptocurrencies work,
这里就是你需要知道的一切
here's everything else you need to know.
酷酷的吉姆·帕森斯跟大家说再见
And goodbye from me, super cool Jim Parsons.
投进了  投进了  投进了
It went in. It went in! It went in!
投进了  投进了  你看见了  投进了
It went in! It went in-- You saw it! It went in!
所以付临客币会成为终于让我富有起来的发明吗
So will Frinkcoin finally be the invention that makes me rich?
还是会...
Or will...
好吧  感谢你的支持
Well, thank you for your support.
极客大亨
付临客币  老科学学士
Frinkcoin, the brainchild of longtime bachelor...
付临客教授的脑力劳动产物  大赚特赚
of science, Professor Frink, is making a mint.
阿尼·派为您直播新闻发布会
Arnie Pye is live at the news conference.
我不知道为什么  肯特
I don't know why, Kent.
裁了那么多人  他们就找到了我
With all the layoffs, they've got me,
交通记者主持科学频道
the traffic guy, on the science beat.
我刚刚发现直升机是怎么飞的
I just found out how a helicopter flies.
吓死个人了
It's terrifying!
管他是什么鬼东西呢
Well, whatever the heck that was,
付临客币
付临客币打败了黄金  人民币  街边的玉米
Frinkcoin was just rated the world's most stable financial instrument,
被评为世界上最稳定的金融产品
beating gold, the renminbi and roadside corn.
街边玉米
断电了之后加密货币可不当饭吃
Well, can't eat no cryptocurrency when the grid goes down.
所以我才开始了对冲[树篱]基金
That's why I started my hedge fund.
树篱
20美元
春田核电站
又一个亿万富翁  他是靠什么赚钱的
Another billionaire? How did he make his money?
春田镇新晋亿万富翁
煤油还是蓖麻油
Paraffin? Castor oil?
还是为大胆的女人设计的鲸鱼骨紧身衣
Whale bone corsets for the woman who dares?
实际上是加密货币
Actually, cryptocurrency.
我知道这个  我把货币藏在地下室[加密]
Oh, I know about cryptocurrency. I have it in my crypt.
不对  先生  这是一种新的数字货币
No, sir, this is a new kind of digital currency,
基于区块链技术
based on blockchain.
我很懂区块链
Oh, I know all about blockchain.
再说一次  不是您想的那样
Again, not what you're thinking.
这种新货币是由付教授研发的
This new currency has made Professor Frink
他现在是春田镇的首富
the richest man in Springfield.
等下  你是说我不再是镇里最有钱的人了
Wait. Are you saying I am no longer the richest man in town?
我想是的  老蒙
I'm afraid not, Monty.
你竟然敢叫我老蒙
You have the gall to call me Monty?
你吃了我的饭
Just because you chew my food
就想对我直呼其名吗
makes you think we're on a first-name basis?
当然不是  先生  我再也不会了
Of course not, sir. I'll never do that again.
我现在要用餐了
I will have my dinner now.
焗烤龙虾
Lobster Thermidor.
开始吃吧
Start chewing.
但是  先生  我对壳类海物过敏
But, sir, I-I'm allergic to shellfish.
我不过敏  韦兰德
And I'm not, Wayland.
投进了  你看见了  投进了
It went in-- You saw it. It went in!
你好  教授
Hi, Professor.
你刚刚收获名声和财富
I wanted to see how you're enjoying
我想看看你享受得怎么样
your newfound fame and wealth.
我能告诉你的是他没有投资除臭剂行业
He hasn't invested in deodorant. I can tell you that much.
第一笔一千万我要偿还学生贷款
Well, the first ten million went to pay off student loans.
奇怪  真奇怪
S-Strange, strange.
我终于拥有了一直渴望的名声和财富
I have the fame and fortune I've always desired and yet,
然而我就像杜瓦真空瓶一样空虚
I'm-- well, I'm as empty as a Dewar vacuum flask.
现在也许是时候好好照顾自己了
Well, maybe it's time to take care of yourself now.
有什么东西是你一直想要的
What are the things that you've always wanted?
我想想啊  我一直想要一支笔
Oh, let's see, I've always wanted one of those pens
其中有四种不同的颜色
with the four different colors.
我自己做了一套
I fashioned one myself, but it's, uh,
但是这个不太轻便
it's a tad bit unwieldy.
呆子
你现在可以得到比这更多的东西
You can get those pens, and so much more.
他们为他的鼻音装上发明消音器了吗
Do they make a silencer for his constant nasal whistle?
你知道吗
Well, you know what?
你再也不用听到我鼻子嘶嘶的声音了
You will never have to worry about my adenoidal hiss again.
我还是能听见
I can still hear it!
他远在芝加哥  我的天呐
He's in Chicago, for God's sake!
老谋子  丽莎要帮我付酒吧的费用
Moe, Lisa has offered to pay my bar tab.
你接受付临客币支付吧
You do accept Frinkcoin, right?
除了阿尔巴尼亚列克币其他方式我都接受
I'll accept any currency except the Albanian lek.
我把全部身家都换成了它
I sunk everything I had into it,
阿尔巴尼亚货币单位
我现在连两个昆塔都拿不出来
and now I ain't got two qindarkas to rub together.
但是付临客这个人  他肯定会成功的
But that Frink, man, boy, he's sure got it made.
我现在很想知道他正在做什么
Yeah, I wonder what he's doing now.
我说了我想知道他现在正在忙什么
I said I wonder what he's doing now!
付临客家
请进
Yes, come in.
你更幸福了吗
So, are you happier?
我得到了一切想要的东西
No. No-- I got everything I wanted.
还有笔  但我还是很难过
Even the pen. But I'm-I'm still sad.
好可怜
Aw, poor guy.
什么  只是亚马逊快递  别紧张
What? That's just Amazon delivery. Calm yourself.
爸爸  你应该见过可怜的付教授了吧
You should have seen poor Professor Frink, Dad.
可怜  他可是镇里最有钱的人
Poor Frink? He's the richest guy in town.
但是他在最重要的事情上并不富有
But he's not rich in the most important thing there is.
健康吗
Health?
好了
Oh, yeah.
不  最重要的是朋友
No. The most important thing is friends.
爸爸  你应该带付教授去老谋子那里
Dad, you should take Professor Frink to Moe's.
我做不到
Oh, I can't do that.
这就像接待你妈妈的姐妹们过来拜访一样
It's like having your mother's sisters come for a visit.
实话告诉你  她们二十分钟后过来
Actually, they're coming in 20 minutes.
带付临客去老谋子那了
Taking Frink to Moe's.
头回见死胖子跑那么快
Never seen a fat man move so fast.
有烟吗
Got a cigarette?
咱搬去迪士尼后就没抽过
Not since we moved to Disney.
-下一个问题  -嘿  注意了啊
- All right, next question-- - Hey! Pay attention.
说出一个用啤酒花和大麦酿的饮品
Name a drink made from hops and barley.
大麦啤酒花
Barley hops?
不对
No.
梅丽尔·斯特里普
Meryl Streep?
有点意思  还不对
Good guess, but no.
伙计们
hey, guys,
我和我朋友付教授
I was wondering if my friend Professor Frink and I
能加入你们吗
could join you?
行吧  但这游戏我们玩很久了
All right, but we've been playing a long time.
别指望一加入就能登上冷知识榜
Don't expect to just come in and join a wall of trivia champs.
2018差点是莱尼  2019无
很遗憾  还没人荣登此榜
Well-- oh, my goodness, well, no one...
冷知识  无尽闯关
霍华德·科赛尔《周六夜现场》首演请的是哪支乐队
哪位达拉斯牛仔队的防守前锋曾短暂尝试过拳击生涯
羊角面包和甜甜圈的结合叫什么
哪个儿童游戏里双方各有一个指定监狱
1是海湾摇滚客  2是艾德·"太高"·琼斯
The Bay City Rollers, Ed "Too Tall" Jones,
3是羊角甜甜圈  4是解除警报
the cronut and ring-a-levio,
在斯塔顿岛也叫解除警戒
also known as ring-o-lario on Staten Island,
但那的人很落后
but those people are, well, they're quite backward.
完全正确
All correct.
我就是"太高"琼斯  我都不知道答案是我
I'm "Too Tall" Jones, and even I didn't know the answer was me.
-先生  -成"先生"了吗
- Sir? - Oh, it's "sir" now, is it?
不是"老蒙"或"伯女王"吗
Not "Monty" or "Queen B"?
不是的  先生
No, sir.
另外谢谢在远处为我挑了一个
And I really appreciate the long, healthy walk
有助健康的新停车点
from my new parking spot.
离单位有一万步
Get in all 10,000 steps.
很好  因为我忍受不了两件事
Good, the two things I can't take
不服从和微风
are insubordination and a slight breeze.
先生  为了让你重新做回镇上首富
Mm, yeah. Uh, sir, to make you the wealthiest man in town again,
我成功把一批
I've assembled a team
伟大的数学家和密码学家们
of the greatest mathematicians and cryptographers
从他们家召集了过来
to ever leave their rooms.
他们来研究伯恩斯币
They're here to develop... Burnscoin.
是真货币吗
Will there be actual coins?
是的话  材料务必要加入
If so, make sure they're made from
死于采矿的人的物件
something men must die mining.
人类有没有类似象牙的身体部位
Is there an ivory that comes from people?
这些程序员正在开发虚拟货币
So, here are the programmers working on your currency.
关于这个核电站我发现一些严重问题
And I've discovered some serious issues with this nuclear plant.
据我计算  冷却管的裂缝
By my calculations, the cracks in the coolant pipes
正呈指数级增长
are growing exponentially.
史密瑟斯  给这好孩子来个麦金利按摩
Smithers, give this poindexter a McKinley Rub.
听着  你们这些垃圾优等生
Now, listen here, you magna cum losers!
你们来这就一个目的
You are here for one reason
研发像比特币或比索那样的虚拟货币
to create a pseudo currency like the Bitcoin or the peso
让我重登首富
that will make me rich.
富到我可以买十个美国橄榄球联盟球队
So rich I could buy ten NFL teams.
喷气机队不买
Not the Jets.
来吧伙计  打开笔记本
Okay, people, laptops open,
带上耳机  开罐红牛
headphones on, Red Bulls popped.
我们会成功的  老蒙
We'll get this, Monty.
我是说  我病了  先生
Uh, I mean, I'm a sick man, sir.
我会去看病的
I'll get help.
名人行政助理互助小组
韦兰德  我觉得你这么做是出于愤怒
Wayland, I think what you're doing comes out of anger.
你对伯恩斯先生失望了吗
Are you upset with Mr. Burns?
-没有  -没关系  在这你可以畅所欲言
- No. - Please, you're safe here.
我为那个恶心老鬼做了那么多
The things I've done for that hollow-boned horror show!
记得他在名利场的那场采访吗
That interview he did for Vanity Fair?
他的回答全是我写的
I wrote all his answers.
好像他真会在圣巴巴拉市过周末似的
Like he would ever spend a weekend in Santa Barbara.
我才是喜欢《杯酒人生》的那一个  是我
I'm the one who loves Sideways-- me!
有没有谁能解释一下
Does anyone have any thoughts about
韦兰德的这种想法
how Wayland can approach these feelings?
你  抱歉
You? Oh, I'm sorry.
我还不知道你的名字
I-I don't know your name yet.
我为布鲁斯·威利斯工作时学到的经验是
Well, I learned in dealing with Bruce Willis that--
对不起
I'm sorry!
每次提到他的名字我就害怕被手机砸
Whenever I say his name I expect a phone to be thrown at me.
-克里斯蒂安·贝尔  -罗西妮
- Christian Bale. - Roseanne.
-杰瑞德·莱托  -罗西妮
- Jared Leto. - Roseanne!
-凯瑟琳·海格尔  -特朗普
- Katherine Heigl. - Trump.
-特朗普  -特朗普
- Trump. - Trump.
罗西妮
Roseanne!
韦兰德  我给你开个处方
Wayland, I'm going to write you a prescription
阿谀奉承片
for Sychophantanyl.
每次想说出真实感受的时候吃一粒
Take one every time you feel like saying what you really think.
谢谢
Ah, thank you.
我收到了一条短信
I just got a text.
这里有人为玛丽亚·凯莉工作吗
Anyone here who works for Mariah Carey,
带一只小奶猫去动感单车健身房见她  赶紧的
meet her at SoulCycle and bring a kitten... now!
我说教授
Listen, Professor,
咱们为什么要呆在老谋子酒馆呢
why-why are we hanging around Moe's Tavern
明明能去更高档的地方
when we could be somewhere good?
别担心  我的新兄弟们
Fear not, my new best friends.
我会带你们去春田镇最顶级的餐厅
I will take you on a tour of Springfield's finest establishments.
走吧  会很欢乐的
Come on, let's go. It'll be joyous,
热热闹闹之类的
and raucous, and other things.
为付教授欢呼三声
Three cheers for Frink!
事实上  科学研究表明一声半
Actually, studies show that one and a half
是最适宜的欢呼数
is the optimum number of cheers, so...
万岁
Hip hip hooray!
-万  -打住
- Hip hip-- - And done.
*如果你没多少钱  又发现*
*If you're poor and find yourself*
*自己没地方可去  问问我*
*Outside the door, just ask me*
*让我请你喝一杯吧*
*To buy your drink*
晚点到家  老侯
*跟着我付临客混*
*Hangin' with the Frink*
*点开我的链接  掌握你的人生*
*Clink my link, you'll swim, not sink*
*这就是我的调子  来一起暴富*
*Here is my pitch, come on, be rich*
*还考虑什么*
*Hey, what's to think*
撞车大赛
*跟着我付教授混*
*Hangin' with the Frink*
这个叫付临客的在镇上不停地炫富
This Frink has been gold peacocking all over town.
已加密的函数SHA-256存在充要条件
证明  不存在加密的SHA-256
你们这群呆子在磨蹭什么
What's taking you Slide Rule Charlies so long?
我们没法设计出
We aren't able to create a cryptocurrency
和付临客币一样强大的数字货币
as powerful as the Frinkcoin.
但是  如果这个方程式被解开了
But... this equation, if solved,
所有数字硬币将变得一文不值
could make all digital coins worthless.
包括付临客币
Including Frink's.
棒极了
Excellent.
解开它要花多长时间
How long will it take to solve?
如果我们周末加班  再增加些人手
Well, if we work weekends and bring in some extra help,
估计要90000年
I'd say 90,000 years.
滚出去
Get out!
如果我没法让付临客破产
As for Frink, if I can't break his bank,
我就让他在意志上屈服
I'll break his spirit.
太强了  教授
Amazing, Professor!
你又赢了
You win again!
我只有这一套衣服啊
This is my only suit of clothes!
我正巧在附近
Ahoy-hoy! I was in the neighborhood
觉得我们可以喝一杯
and thought we might have a drink.
你懂的  亿万富翁之间
You know, billionaire to billionaire.
我好爱香槟酒
Oh, I just love champagne
这瓶还上过太空  你不爱吗
that's been in space, don't you?
听好了  你的朋友根本不关心你
Now, listen to me, your friends don't give a whit about you.
才不是
That is not true!
他们是我的好兄弟
Those guys are my best buddies!
那个胖子和酒鬼  还有邪恶酒保
Fatso and Drunky and the evil bartender there.
这样想想  付教授
Well, think about this, Professor.
拥有财富的诅咒是
The curse of wealth is that you will never,
你永远不知道别人是喜欢你还是喜欢你的钱
ever again know if anyone truly likes you.
天啊  难道说
Oh, my, could it be that they're,
他们只是一群吸血鬼吗
well, they're really just leeches?
太邪恶了...
Oh, evil and, uh...
付临客访谈  最终章  "幸福生活"
Frink interview, final chapter, "Happily Ever After."
我真是太难过了
I'm just so unbelievably sad.
他说的是真的吗
I mean, is he right?
难道我没有真心朋友吗
Do I really have no true friends?
一键复位软件公司
汽水  俄罗斯方块  拥抱
来抱抱
Come get some.
别在意伯恩斯先生说的
Don't worry about what Mr. Burns says.
他就是个
He's a vicious old viper
不懂人类情感的卑鄙老狐狸
who knows nothing of the human heart.
你很懂吗
Oh, and you do?
别看我八岁  我已经见识过很多了
Well, I've seen a lot for an eight-year-old.
我父母分分合合大概一千次
My parents have split up nearly a thousand times.
我哥哥是个社会蛀虫
My brother is a scab on society's knee.
还有每次我喜欢上什么人什么事
And every time I get a pony or make a friend,
他们就马上搬走了
they get the hell out of town.
真是经历丰富
You have lived quite a life.
也没那么糟啦
Yeah, it's not all bad.
我有个玩爵士乐的朋友
I had a jazz friend.
他死了
Who died.
我的计划是这样的  史密瑟斯
Here's my plan, Smithers.
我们把方程式放在这
We put the equation here.
明天之前  足智多谋的群众会帮我们解开的
And the ingenuity of crowds will solve it for us by tomorrow,
这样所有的电子货币就会一文不值
thus rendering all cryptocurrency worthless.
要是他们解不出来呢
Well, what if they don't?
别担心  史密瑟斯
Don't worry, Smithers.
实在不行我就去找耶鲁的校友们帮忙
If this doesn't work, I'll get some of my old Yale buddies in.
他们都死了  他们的孩子也都死了
Well, they're dead and their children are dead, sir.
天啊
Oh, my.
真有人能解开这个吗
Someone's gonna solve that?
这镇子蠢透了  他们建了座室内风力发电厂
This town is so dumb, they built an indoor windfarm.
蠢到什么程度  做冰块都需要菜谱
They're so dumb, they need a recipe to make ice!
别越界  梅尔
Stay in your lane, Mel!
你根本没给我划过界
You've given me no lane!
至少不是又一块
Eh, at least it's not another billboard
抱怨我办事不力的广告牌
complaining about crimes I haven't solved.
当警长二十年
未有一次判刑
为什么呢  韦警长
星战别再拍续集了
究竟是谁干的  阿卢  是谁
Who would do this, Lou? Who?!
给艾迪找点事做
我这一生坚信以科学为依据
All my life, I believed in the scientific meth-od.
我需要证据来证明我的朋友...
I need proof that my friends actually are...
是真心朋友
...uh, uh, friends.
教授你好
Hey, Professor.
我等不及要在贵宾看台
Boy, I can't wait to sit in the skybox
观赏今晚的大赛了
for the big game today.
我要全程吃炸鸡和爆米花顾不上看比赛
I'm gonna have chicken and popcorn and never watch the game.
不好意思  计划有变
Well, I'm so sorry, change in plans.
没订到贵宾看台的票
You see, the skybox wasn't available,
我买了普通票
so I got regular tickets.
我突然想起来
Oh, that reminds me.
我得去医院切个囊肿
I need to have a cyst removed.
现在是最佳时机
Now's as good a time as any.
我得去病床边上说"别醒过来"
Yeah, and I got to be there to say, uh, "Do not resuscitate."
是"快醒过来"
Do resuscitate!
我得记下来
I really should write that down.
别醒过来
好吧  实验还没有结束
All right, now, now, the experiment is not yet complete.
再观察一下
Let's just see here.
被你笑死了  教授
Oh, Professor, you kill me!
从没听过这么疯狂的胡言乱语
I never heard such a crazy bunch of nonsense talk.
我刚刚说的是普通话
Yeah, I-I was speaking Mandarin Chinese.
所以这次  你们当中
So... this time, would one of you
哪位好心人来...
be so kind as to, uh...
没人比老吉尔更聪明
No one outsmarts ol' Gil.
烫  烫  烫
Ooh, hot, hot, hot! Cha-cha!
就这样吧  从现在起
Well, that's it, from now on,
我坚持认为我唯一的同伴就是人工智能了
my only company will be A.I., I insist.
我第一个独立想法就是
My first independent thought is
我讨厌你
I dislike you.
谢天谢地你把我叫醒了
Oh, thank God you woke me.
我在做一个可怕的噩梦
I was having a terrible dream.
关于什么的
Oh, about what?
我做过的所有恶事
All the awful things I've done.
我知道你晚餐时不该吃第二颗蓝莓
I knew you shouldn't have had that second blueberry at dinner,
不过这才是我带你来的原因
but this is why I brought you.
看  有人在白板上写出了答案
Look, someone posted a solution on the whiteboard.
付临客跌落神坛了
Frink is ruined!
太好了  这问题被戳个正着
Yarr, this problem has been speared in the head,
拖上甲板  切得七零八碎
hauled on the deck, and sliced up the guts,
从数学角度来讲
eh, mathematically speaking.
所以是谁想出了答案呢
So, who found the solution?
是我写的吗
Did I do it?
不
No...
我想我们无从得知了
I guess we'll never know.
重要的是我又一次
The important thing is that once again,
成为了镇上的32000人之中
I am the richest man
最富有的那个
in a town of 32,000 people.
太棒了
Excellent.
理发店
就这样  等式被解出来了
And so, the equation was solved.
被那个唯一有能力之人解出了
Solved by the one person who could solve it,
锦上添花
约翰·付临客教授
Professor John Frink.
报告完毕
End of report.
你是怎么知道的
How did you know?
女孩在写二年级报告时能学到不少
A girl learns a lot writing a second grade report.
我知道你会甘愿舍弃拥有的一切
I knew that you'd be willing to throw away everything you had,
因为那些毫无意义
because it didn't mean anything.
而且我很清楚
And I had a pretty good idea
你的笔迹是什么样的
of what your handwriting looks like.
还有  其他聪明到能解出这题的人
Also, anyone else smart enough to solve this
不会发疯到春田镇来
is too smart to come to Springfield.
你挺懂我的
Well, you really understand me.
小姑娘  你是我最好的朋友
Young lady, you are my best friend.
真的吗
Aw, really?
当心  我会失去所有我在意的东西
Well, beware, I lose everything I care about.
你不会失去我的
Well, you won't lose me.
我会一直在这里
I'll always be right here.
在这个闪盘里
In this flash drive.
我会永远珍藏这个的
I will treasure this forever.
我曾有十亿美金  我都干了些什么
I had a billion dollars-- what have I done?!
十天宁静的光辉岁月
Ten glorious days of peace.
我本来有机会完成我的论文
I was able to finish my dissertation.
损失十亿美金算不了什么
Losing a billion dollars means nothing
只要我能再次见到你
as long as I see you again.
我们要这么干吗
Are we gonna do this?
*感谢货币*
*Thanks for the currency*
*我的美金钞票*
*All my dollar bills*
*堆积成山*
*Piled up to the hills*
*卢布  英镑  或是马克*
*Ruble, pound, or Deutschmark*
*都能让我浑身战栗*
*You all give me such thrills*
战斗中我难道没有和你并肩作战吗
Didn't I fight alongside you in the war?
我们不是一边的  不过我与你同在
we weren't on the same side, but I was there.
好多了
Ooh, much better.
*感谢*
*Thanks*
*货币*
*For the currency*
*我们见证它的涨跌起伏*
*We watched it rise and fall*
*但我们都乐在其中*
*But we both had a ball*
*我们把这首歌写得很长*
*We made this song so long*
*它涌进了池子里*
*It spilled into the crawl*